くっ…！
契約に基づき… 命じる！
震えよ 我が 右腕！
漆黒の炎をまといて
我が 望みを満たせ！
Shiver, my right hand...
くっ… だあっ！
By the contract we made, I order you
ああ～！ これじゃ
から揚げ 温められないよ～
to wreathe yourself in black flame
and grant my desire!
いいんですか？ ラボメンになると
ああいうのに
つきあわされますよ？
あっ…
横暴だよ～ じゃあ オカリン
新しく電子レンジ 買ってきてよ～
Now I can't heat up my kara-age!
フフッ そんな金は ない
You sure about this?
Mayuri, this is no longer a microwave.
It's a time machine!
If you join the lab, you'll be dealing with this all day.
うっ 俺を写すのは 禁止だと
言ったはずだ！
記念に…
え？
That's not fair!
とにかく 撮るな！
ん…
Then go buy me a new microwave, Okarin.
よ～し プログラム おわた！
I don't have the money.
電話レンジ ｾｶﾝﾄﾞｴﾃﾞｨｼｮﾝ ﾊﾞｰｼﾞｮﾝ1.03
完成～！
I told you not to photograph me.
It's to celebrate.
これで 電話レンジの携帯から
Anyway, no photos!
好きな番号に
Ｄメールを転送できるぜい！
Okay, done programming.
でかしたぞ ダル！
Phone Microwave, 2nd Ed., Version 1.03 is done.
それじゃあ 実験再開ね
本当に タイムマシン…
Now you can use the
Phone Microwave's cell phone
絶対に 口外するなよ？
な～！ でも 店長さんに
また 怒られないかな～？
to send a D-mail to any phone you like!
You did it, Daru!
ううっ…
Then let's continue our experiments.
うん…？
バイト戦士～！
Is it really a time machine?
お～い トゥットゥル－！
トゥットゥル－！
Don't tell anyone, okay?
まゆり 静かに！ ああっ…！
ミスターブラウンは？
誰？
But don't you think the landlord
will get mad at us?
お父さんは ﾐｽﾀｰﾌﾞﾗｳﾝなんかじゃ…
ああ 店長なら 出張サービス中
Part-time warrior!
しばらく
帰ってこないんじゃないかな？
ああっ 本当か？
でなきゃ ここでサボって…
Mayuri, be quiet!
Where's Mr. Braun?
Who's that?
Don't call my dad Mr. Braun...
You mean the boss? He's out on a call.
I don't think he'll be back for a while.
まゆり…
うん！
Is that true?!
If it weren't, I couldn't screw around outside.
ああっ…！
Mayuri.
Okay.
あっ…
おお？
おお～！
これは…！
あっ 光った！
Received Mail
Date Received: 2010/07/29 13:43
From: Mayuri
Subject: (None)
Tutturu
This is...
I saw a light.
Divergence Singularity
はあ～
ｼﾞｭｰｼｰからあげﾅﾝﾊﾞｰﾜﾝの方が
おいしいんだけどな～
Juicy Kara-age #1 would taste better...
なっ… はっ！
おい ドクペが ないではないか！
Hey, there's no Dr Pepper!
売り切れてたの
売り切れていたのなら
They were out.
見つけるまで探す！ それが
ﾄﾞｸﾄﾙﾍﾟｯﾊﾟﾘｱﾝというものではないか
If they're out, keep looking until you find some!
That's what it means to be a Dr Pepperian.
ああ…
なかったものは なかったんだから
They didn't have any.
What do you want me to do about it?
仕方ないでしょ？ 要らないの？
You want some or not?
うおっ… うう…
まったく… 野菜不足を気にしてる
マッドサイエンティストが
Jeez...
What kind of mad scientist worries about
not getting enough vegetables?
どこの世界にいるというのだ
では 円卓会議を始める！
Let's begin the Round Table.
つ～か 窓 開けよ 暑いっしょ～？
It's hot in here. Let's open a window.
何をしているのだ ダル！
What are you doing, Daru?
機関に 我々の秘密を知られたら
どうする！
What if the Organization discovers our secret...
妄想 乙
うん…？
Delusion fail!
うん？
What's a Round Table?
うん…
これより 過去を司る女神作戦を
第２段階に進め…
We will now move Operation Urd to stage 2,
Ｄメールを
より実践的に使う実験を…
and run experiments to make the D-mail
行おうと思う…
more practical.
夏は 麦茶だよね～
萌郁さんも 飲む？
During summer, you need barley tea.
Want some, too, Moeka-san?
実践的って 何するんだお？
Practical? What are we going to do?
過去を変える！
Change the past.
待って そんなの 危険すぎる！
Wait... That's too dangerous.
もしも タイムパラドックスが
起こったら…
If you create a time paradox...
助手よ お前は 科学者として
Assistant, as a scientist,
Ｄメールを使い
過去を変えられるかどうか
aren't you interested in whether we can
alter the past, using the D-Mail?
確かめたくはないのか？
そっ それは…
でも 何を変えるの？
W-Well...
But what will we change?
いい質問だ
Good question.
俺が 本作戦において
成し遂げたいこと
Here's what I want to accomplish
with this operation...
それは…
宝くじを 当てることだ！
Win the lottery.
オカリン…
まゆしぃは 悲しいです
Okarin... Mayushii is very sad.
僕は 賛成～ 金があれば
ＰＣパーツ買えるし
I'm in.
If I had money, I could buy
new parts for the computer,
メイクイ－ンにも 行き放題だお
もっとね…
and I could go to May Queen all I want.
We should work toward world peace.
世界が平和になる方法とか
考えるべきじゃ ないかな～？
例えば 世界中の人たちが
ウーパクッションを持てる…
Like give everyone in the world an Upa cushion...
岡部 志 低すぎ
Okabe, that's really lame.
過去を変えられるかどうかの
実験なのだ！
It's an experiment to see
if we can change the past.
一番 分かりやすいではないか！
That would be the easiest way to tell!
でも 目的は お金でしょ？
黙れ セレブセブンティーン
But basically, you just want money, right?
Shut up, Celeb 17!
セッ… セレ… はあ？
Cele... Huh?
セレブセブンティーン
Celeb 17!
親の金で ホテル住まいを
しているような人間に
I don't want to hear anything from a woman
とやかく言われる 筋合いは
ない！
living in a hotel on her parent's money!
私は エイティーンだ
I'm eighteen.
つ～かさあ 宝くじにも
いろいろ あるっしょ？
But there are all kinds of lottery tickets.
どれにするん？
うむ それは…
Which one do you want?
Well...
うん…？
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
あっ いや…
No...
萌郁は どこに行った？
Where'd Moeka go?
あれ？
はっ… うっ…！
Huh?
うっ…
待て～い！
Wait!
よいしょ…
まったく… 油断も隙もない！
Sheesh... Can't take my eyes
off you for a second.
返事 なかったから…
Because you didn't respond.
I really want to borrow
the IBN 5100.
Please...
It's okay, right?
なっ…！
これは もしや
Is she supposed to be a valley girl LOL?
スイーツ(笑)ってやつ？
クリスティーナ
勝手に動き回らないように
Christina, keep a close eye on her,
しっかり見張っているのだぞ！
えっ？
so she doesn't wander around!
見張ってろって 言われても…
あ…
How am I supposed to do that?
萌郁さん ラボ 見たいの～？
Do you want to see the lab, Moeka-san?
じゃあ 後で 案内したげるね
まゆしぃ 得意なんだよ～？
I'll show you around later.
Mayushii is good at that!
紅莉栖ちゃんにも したげたんだ～
I did it for Kurisu-chan, too!
まずは どこから
見せようかな～？
Where should I start?
なるへそ～ ロト６ね～
I see.
The Loto 6.
毎週木曜日に
当選番号が 発表されている
Every Thursday,
the winning numbers are announced.
そいつを 過去に送るのだ
We'll send the numbers to the past.
本当にやるの？
他に いい代案があるのか？
We're really doing this?
You have any other ideas?
うっ…
当選番号だけど どれにする～？
Which number do you want?
ちなみに １等は…
By the way, first prize is...
ちょ… ２億円とか
えっ
200,000,000 yen!
にっ ２億円？
待て ダル！
200,000,000 yen?
Wait, Daru.
２億円は ちょっと…
えっ ええ？
200,000,000 yen is a bit much.
いっ １等は
さすがに 目立ち過ぎる…
First prize would draw too much attention.
お… 俺は 機関に
追われてる身だからな
The Organization is chasing me, after all.
ビビったな
にっ ２等は？
You got cold feet, didn't you?
What's second prize?
えっと 2,300万円？
23,000,000 yen.
３等！
Third?
700,000.
70万円
そっ それ～！
We'll go with that!
岡部って 結構 チキンね
それが タイムパラドックスを…
Okabe's chicken, isn't he?
That's coming from someone
worried about a time paradox, Cel-7?
で これがウーパクッション！
And this is the Upa cushion!
疲れたときとか 元気がないときに
むぎゅ～ってするの
When you're tired or feeling down,
you give it a hug, like this!
ん…
でね こっちが 冷蔵庫
And this is the fridge!
今日の中身は～
What's inside today?
あの…
うん？
Um...
おい 閃光の指圧師！
うん…？
Hey!
Shining Finger!
お前に ラボメンとしての
最初の任務を与える
Here's your first Lab Member mission.
え…
おお 初仕事だね
Ooh, your first job!
Think of what to write in the D-mail.
Ｄメールの文面を 考えるのだ
何も知らない１週間前の俺に
Something that will make the me of
ロト６を買おうと思わせる
文章をな
one week ago want to buy a Lotto-6 ticket.
７日前だから…
168時間170秒ってところかしら
Seven days ago
would be 168 hours,
so about 170 seconds would do it?
ふむ…
I guess that's it.
Buy Lotto-6
You'll win!
こんなもんだろう
じゃあ 準備完了ね
Okay, we're ready.
フフ… ついに 運命石の扉を
開く時が 来たな！
At last, the time has come to open Steins Gate!
また それ？
ほんっと 飽きないわね
That again?
You really never tire of it, do you?
お前こそ いちいち水を差すな！
And you need to stop whining
about it every time.
うん？
あっ？
楽しそうだったから…
You looked like you were having fun.
はっ？
べっ 別に楽しくなんか！
I-It's not like I'm having fun, all right?
それにしても この助手
ツンデレである
That said, our assistant sure is a tsundere.
誰が ツンデレだ！
Who's a tsundere?!
おお～ 牧瀬氏
ツンデレの意味が 分かるん？
Ooh, Miss Makise, you know what a tsundere is?
へっ？
ふ～ん？
I don't!
しっ 知らないわよ！
いや 確かに知ってる反応だったな
No, you definitely responded like you did.
知らないったら 知らないってば！
I said I don't!
んじゃ レンジ起動させるぜよ～？
Okay, I'm starting up the microwave.
そんなの 危険すぎる！
That's too dangerous.
もしも タイムパラドックスが
起こったら…
If you create a time paradox...
うっ くっ…
いや… 何を 弱気になってんだ…
Why am I so scared?
エル･プサイ…
El Psy Congroo!
コングルゥ！
Sending...
Sent
うっ ううっ！
おかり～ん…
Okarin!
お～かり～ん
オカリン？
ああっ！
Okarin!
はっ… あっ…
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
Wh-What was that?
いっ 今のは… はっ！
あっ…
俺は… 何分ぐらい
ここに立ってた？
How many minutes have I been standing here?
え？ う～ん 30秒くらいかな～？
About thirty seconds, I guess.
30秒？
Thirty seconds?
覚えてないの？ さっきまで
Ｄメールで過去を変える実験の
You don't remember?
We were just talking about an experiment
to see if we could change the past with a D-mail.
話をしてたじゃない そしたら…
And then...
You ran over to Phone Microwave-chan
急に 電話レンジちゃんの所に来て
はあ はあって言い出して…
and started panting...
Mayushii, can you say "panting" again?
あっ ああ…
Stop it, pervert!
うん？
あっ…
届いてる…
It's here.
Buy Lotto-6
You'll win!
岡部 ホントに 大丈夫？
Okabe... Are you really all right?
金は!? ロト６だ！
えっ ええ？
Where's the money?
The Lotto-6!
セレセブ 俺は ３等を
当てたのか!?
Cel-7, did I win third prize?
セレセブ言うな！ って何の話よ
Don't call me Cel-7...
What are you talking about?
なっ 何って お前…
What do you mean? You...
オカリン？
うっ…
Okarin?
The experiment?
実験だ！
俺たちは Ｄメールを使って
We did an experiment to see if we could
change the past with the D-mail...
過去を変える実験を…
だから 今
どんな内容のメールがいいか
We were just talking about what we could
do for the experiment.
みんなで 話してたんじゃない？
ええっ…
まゆしぃは～
Mayushii wants something that will bring about world peace!
世界が 平和になる方法とか
いいな～
Like giving everyone in the world an Upa cushion!
ほ… 本当に… 覚えてないのか？
You really don't remember...
んっ…
あっ
どうぞ～
Come in!
It's Ruka-kun!
あっ るか君 いらっしゃい
Welcome!
あっ！
凶真さん すみませんでした！
るか君？
Kyouma-san, I'm sorry!
Ruka-kun?
これ…
あっ！
This...
０２ １２ １８… 同じだ
02, 12, 18...
It's the same.
ルカ子！ お前 これをどこで！
あっ
Rukako! Where did you get this?
えっ あの… 僕…
Um... You gave me the numbers.
凶真さんに 数字を教えてもらって
俺が？
I did?
当たるかもしれない数字だから
買ってみろって…
You said to buy it since it might win.
Wh-When?
ええっ いつ？
One week ago.
１週間前です
おお オカリンは 予知能力者だね
Wow, Okarin's psychic!
で るか氏 ロト６ 当てたん？
So, Ruka, did you win?
それが…
Well... I got one of the numbers wrong.
番号を１つ
間違えてしまって…
えっ… あっ！
うお～ 惜しい！ 惜しすぐる！
So close!
Too close!
Okabe, did you use the Phone Microwave to...
岡部… あんた
まさか 電話レンジで…
ああ…！
ドクペが ないではないか！
Hey, there's no Dr Pepper!
なかったものはなかったんだから
仕方ないでしょ！
They didn't have any.
What do you want me to do about it?
俺は
確かに Ｄメールを送ったはずだ
I sent the D-mail.
But there's no record of it.
しかし 送信履歴がない
過去が 書き換えられた
ということか
The past has been changed?
あいつらは
実験のことを覚えていなかった
They didn't remember the experiment,
even though we all talked about it,
and we all observed.
一緒に話し合い
一緒に見ていたはずなのに
Only I remember.
俺だけが 覚えている
俺だけが…
Only I...
この感覚 あの時と一緒だ
This feeling! It's just like back then...
どういうことなんだ？
What is this?
それ なあに？
ああっ…
What's that?
大切なもの
Something important.
あっ！
どうした？
What's wrong?
あっ… ああ
洗脳されたような顔してる
You look like you've been brainwashed.
Brainwashed...
洗脳…
フフッ… そうかもしれない
It's possible.
洗脳されたのは
俺の方か あいつらの方…
But was I the one brainwashed... Or were they?
何だ？
What?
うっ…
うっ うう…
あっ… チップは入ってない
There's no chip.
大丈夫 洗脳されていない
It's okay.
You're not brainwashed.
チ… チップ？
Chip?
｢洗脳｣って何？
What's brainwashed?
That's...
それは…
それは
I, Hououin Kyouma, will tell you.
この鳳凰院 凶馬が教えてやろう
綯は
岡部 倫太郎が怖いみたいだね
I guess Nae's scared of Okabe Rintarou.
はあ…
聞きたいことがある
There's something I want to ask you.
おっ？
Electricity?
放電？ グラグラ揺れるやつ？
さっき１回あったよね？
You mean when there are all those sparks?
You did it before, didn't you?
10分くらい前にもあったはずだ
There should have been one ten minutes ago.
I didn't notice that one.
そっちは 気付かなかったな…
What about you, Nae?
綯は？
ううん
Nope!
あんたって ホント HENTAIね！
You really are a pervert!
I'm not a pervert!
僕は HENTAIじゃないよ
｢HENTAI紳士｣だよ！
I'm a pervert gentleman!
ねっ？
聞こえてくるって 言ったでしょ？
See?
I told you that you can hear it.
これほどまでとは…
I didn't know it was this bad...
はっ！ もしかして お前
タイムマシンの話も…
Did you hear about the time machine?
うん やるね この！
忠告するが…
Yeah. Nice job, I guess!
Let me warn you...
分かってるって！
誰にも言わないから
I won't tell anyone.
あっ ひょっとして
Are you worried about something
related to the time machine?
タイムマシンのことで
悩んでるとか？
だったらさ
ジョン･タイターに聞い
てみたら？
Then why not ask John Titor?
はっ！
そういえば タイターは言っていた
Come to think of it,
John Titor mentioned this.
｢過去へ行き
そこで過去を変える｣と
If you go to the past and change it,
this alters something called
the divergence number,
｢ダイバージェンスと呼ばれる
数値が変動し
and the world line moves to another world.
世界は 別の世界線に移動する
その移動のとき
When there's a world line move,
people's memories are altered.
変化が生じる以前の世界線での
記憶は消去され
新たな世界線での記憶が
再構築される｣と
And memories of the new world are created.
Ｄメールにより ルカ子がロト６を
買わなかった世界線から
The D-mail moved the world line
from a world where Rukako
didn't buy the Lotto-6 ticket
to one where he did.
買った世界線へと 移動した
The world line changed, and so did the past.
世界線が変わり
過去の流れも変わったのだ
ここは ロト６を当てるための
Ｄメールを
In this world,
I didn't send the D-mail
with the winning Loto 6 number
過去に送らなかった世界
into the past.
It's not that the other Lab Members
don't remember the experiment.
まゆりたちは
覚えていないのではない
実験そのものがなかった世界
なのだ
It never happened.
では なぜ
俺にだけ その記憶があるんだ？
So why do I remember?
うん？ ヤバ！
Oh, no!
綯 何 聞かれても
Nae, whatever he asks,
don't tell him I was slacking off!
あたしがサボってたって
言っちゃダメだよ！
今度 自転車 乗せてくれる？
Will you give me a ride on your bike?
乗せる 乗せる！
I will!
岡部 倫太郎
えっ？
Okabe Rintarou!
I'm on your side, okay?
応援してるからね
おっ おう…
フン フ フンフ… うん？
You!
にゃあろ！
Daddy!
お父さん！
岡部！
Okabe!
俺の娘に何をしていた！
What were you doing with my daughter?!
W-Wait! I wasn't doing anything!
はあ？ まっ 待ってくれ
俺は 何も…
Shut up!
うるせえ！
俺のかわいい娘と 二人っきりで
A guy like you couldn't control himself
if left alone with my daughter!
おめえみてえな野郎が
欲望 抑えきれるわけがねえだろ…
どういう目で ひとのことを！
第一 二人きりでいたわけではない
Do you always think about me like that?
And we weren't alone...
Suzuha was just here.
今の 今まで
鈴羽もここにいたのだ
What? Is that true, Nae?
なに？ 本当か 綯？
約束だから ｢サボってた｣って
言っちゃダメなの
I promised, so I can't say she was slacking off.
な～にい？
あっ…
What?
おら バイト！
くわばら くわばらっ！
Hey! Part-timer!
てめえ サボってやがったな！
You were slacking off!
The 42-inch was left on!
だあ！
42型も つけっぱなしじゃねえか！
I-I'm sorry!
ごっ ごめんなさ～い！
事情は 後で話す
I'll talk about the reason why later.
We're stopping the experiment for today.
今日の実験は中止だ
みんな 解散してくれ
We're done for the day.
あっ？
うう？
オカリン…
Okarin...
So, assistant, you're not going home?
で そこの助手
お前は帰らないのか？
ちょっと 考え事
I'm thinking.
フッ そうか…
I see.
You'd be all alone if you went back to the hotel,
ホテルに帰っても独りぽっちで
さみしいから
so you want me to spend time with you.
この俺に
構ってほしいという訳だな
Right, little Cel-7?
お子様セレセブめ
だから ｢セレセブ｣って言うな
Don't call me Cel-7!
俺は メールをする用事があるのだ
どうしても ここにいたいのならば
I've gotta send this text message.
If you want to stay here, be quiet, The Zombie.
邪魔をせず 静かにしているのだな
蘇りし者
うう…
その呼び方が 一番 カチンとくる
That's the name that bugs me most.
ふう…
恋する乙女が
You're like a girl,
waiting for a message from her crush.
好きな相手からのメールを
待ってるみたい
You really want attention that much?
そんなに 構ってほしいのか？
あっ…
メールの相手 誰なの？
Who was that message to?
John Titor.
ジョン･タイターだ
えっ？
はっ！
Rukako
The Lottery
I'm really sorry
ああ… ああっ
Shining Finger
I Had Fun
Next time, tell me about
the time machine.
It's a promise.
A promise, right?
Bye!
Moeka
ぬぬっ！ このっ このっ…
はあ… うん？
ダル？
Daru?
Hello.
もしもし
あっ オカリン？
Okarin, I realized I made a huge mistake!
実はさ
とんでもないミスに気付いたんだ
んっ… ミス？ 何だ？
A mistake? What?
実は… 実はさ…
Actually... Actually...
ラボに財布忘れてきたお
なに？
I left my wallet at the lab!
What?
So now I can't get into May Queen!
おかげで メイクイーンに
入れないお オカリン…
Okarin, would you...
ぬっ！ うん？
トゥットゥルー！ オカリン
Okarin!
Oh, it's Mayuri.
なんだ まゆりか… あっ
ダルも一緒にいるのだろう？
Daru's with you, right?
金を貸す必要はないからな
分かった
You don't need to lend him money, okay?
Got it.
And so, Okarin, do you feel better?
でね オカリン 元気になった？
まだ だったら
If you don't, you can hug Mayushii's Upa, okay?
まゆしぃのうーぱを
むぎゅうって してもいいからね
Then you'll feel better.
そしたら 元気 出るから
ああ もう 切るぞ
バイト頑張れよ
Okay.
I'm hanging up.
Good luck at work.
うん ありがとう じゃあね
Thanks.
Bye!
Okabe, you're smiling.
岡部 ニヤけてる
んっ？
ぬっ！
ふっ…
ふう… うん？
おっ！
It's here!
来た！
おっ？
I read your message.
｢メールを読みました
Just as you suspected,
あなたの推測どおり 過去を変え
the past was changed, and the world line moved.
世界線が移動したことに
間違いないでしょう
The one thing I don't understand
唯一 分からないことは
is why you retain your memories
from before the change.
あなたに 過去改変前の記憶が
存在しているということです
それは 事実ですか？｣
Is that true?
It's true.
｢事実です 以前にも
同じようなことがありました
Something similar happened before.
What is this?
どういうことでしょう？｣
I don't know.
｢分かりません
メールによる過去改変等
The concept of changing the past
私がいた2036年においても
via e-mail was something that was never
想定されていなかった事象です
envisaged, even in the year 2036.
あなたは 今回 過去を改変し
世界線を移動させました
You changed the past and moved world lines.
But it's never been confirmed that
しかし 世界線を超えて
記憶を維持し
その変動を観測できる人間など
anyone exists who can maintain their memories
over a world-line jump, to observe the change.
今までに
確認されたことはありません
But...
ですが… キョーマ
Kyouma, you may have that power.
あなたには
その力があるのかも知れません｣
You may be able to lead the world
｢あなたならば 世界を導くことが
できるかも知れません
beyond Divergence 1%...
ダイバージェンス１％の
向こう側へ｣
世界を 導くだと…!?
Lead the world?
What lies beyond Divergence 1%?
｢ダイバージェンス１％の
向こう側とは
そこに いったい
何があると言うのですか？｣
What happens then?
Sending...
Sent
ううっ くっ…
What lies beyond it is true freedom.
｢その先にあるのは 真の自由です
If you can't cross that barrier,
その壁を越えなければ
未来はディストピアとなる
the future will become a dystopia.
私の目的は 未来を変えること
My goal is to change the future.
そして その力を持っているのは
あなたかも知れない｣
And you may be the one who has that power.
はっ！ うう…
あっ… 岡部 どうしたの？
Okabe, what's wrong?
What's he talking about?
何を言ってるんだ こいつは…
Me change the future?
俺が 未来を
そんなこと…
That's...
はっ！
ああっ！
あっ ああ…
ああ…
Kyouma,
I want...
...you to be the messiah.
はっ！
フッフッフッ ハッハッハ…
フフフ ハッハハハ…
この俺が 救世主だと？
くだらん！